有些事情*
*There are things
我曾做过*
*I have done
有个地方*
*There's a place
我曾到过*
*I have gone
有只猛兽*
*There's a beast
我曾放过*
*And I let it run
而今它正自由驰骋*
*Now it's running my way
有些事情*
*There are things
叫我追悔莫及*
*I regret
可你无法宽恕*
*But you can't forgive
无法忘怀*
*You can't forget
就让这黑夜*
*So take this night
缠绕我身旁*
*Wrap it around me like a sheet
我深知自己不可饶恕*
*I know I'm not forgiven
但我仍期许得到*
*But I hope that I'll be given
些许的安宁*
*Some peace
一秒  别现在就紧张
One. Don't tense up now.
随牛而动
Go with him.
两秒  就这样  保持节奏
Two. That's it. Stay in rhythm.
三秒  你在想什么  莱恩
Three. What are you doing, Lane?
这可是在骑牛啊
You're tipping in.
四秒  你在搞什么
Four. What's your problem?
坐好  坐回中间去
Get your ass down. Get back in the middle.
五秒  你太弱了
Five. You're weak.
一点太阳都没晒过吧
You got all kinds of daylight under you.
六秒  该死  莱恩应该是你领着牛才对
Six. Damn, Lane, you should be schooling this bull.
七秒  起身  蹄子放下之前坐稳了
Seven. Get up, set your hips before the kick comes down.
漂亮的回转
Nice recovery.
现在就等着直到他再回转躲开你的手
Now just wait till he turns back away from your hand.
莱恩
Lane.
刚刚究竟怎么了
What the hell just happened?
我还正要问你呢
I was about to ask you the same thing.
我没事
I'm fine.
好的
Okay.
我猜卡迪已经告诉你她把我蹬了
I assume Cuddy told you that she dumped me.
没错
She did.
还有我又开始嗑维科丁了
And that I'm back on Vicodin.
她告诉我你嗑了一片
She told me you had taken a Vicodin.
接着我嗑了一堆
And then I took a lot more.
又一堆
And so on.
但你却好得很
But you're fine?
又不是"我很好"的那种好
Well, I'm not fine as in "Fine,"
而是"不用你操心我"的那种
but I'm fine as in "You don't have to worry about me."
因为你把银行帐户取空
Because you cleared out your bank account,
跑来住酒店  还再次嗑药吗
checked into a hotel, and started back on Vicodin?
是因为我很快就会好得不能再好了
Because I'm going to be fine as in "Fine" very soon.
在那之前
Until that happens,
你确信维科丁是
are you sure Vicodin is the...
我腿很疼
My leg hurts.
你已经能应对腿疼了
You've been able to handle the pain.
现在加重了
It's gotten worse.
是心理作用吧
Not physically worse.
加重了就是加重了
Worse is worse.
疼又不能造假
Pain doesn't discriminate.
药也不是做假的
Neither do the pills.
接下来几天份量的维科丁
The Vicodin and the five-star pampering
加上五星级酒店的美食
that I'm gonna get over the next few days
应该足够我熬过这次疼痛
should be enough to get me through it.
所以你并不是想逃避问题
So you don't want to just avoid the issue.
而是不敢面对你正在逃避问题  抱歉是我弄错
You want to avoid avoiding the issue. Sorry.
事情总不如我们假设得那么糟
Nothing is either as bad or as good
也不及我们设想得那么好
as we think it is at the time.
这就是为什么T.O.总是在得分后立马
That's why T.O. mocks his opponents immediately
嘲笑他的对手
after scoring.
他是不会等到第二天他的朋友
He doesn't wait till his friend shows up the next day
给他示范该怎么做
to tell him to deal with it.
再过两周
Two weeks from now,
或许更久  或许短些
maybe a little more, maybe a little less,
我的生活就会像从前一样让人讨厌
my life will be back to its usual level of crappiness.
在那以前  唯一实际的问题就在于
Till then, the only real issue
我要在宾馆费用上花多少钱
is how much I'm gonna spend on hotel charges.
早上好  先生
Good morning, sir.
为您奉上双人豪华早餐
I've got your deluxe breakfast for two.
要不要我数数草莓少了没
Do I have to count the strawberries?
别担心
Don't worry.
您大可完全相信我
You can trust me with anything.
包括您的饮食
Including your food.
在我和他云雨之后
After he and I have sex,
我要撕开他的喉咙
I'm gonna slit his throat
然后在浴缸里给他开膛
and then disembowel him in the bathtub.
没问题  我会取消晨间客房服务
Oh, no problem. I'll cancel the morning maid service.
需要我让她们稍后为您
Would you like me to have them clean up later
掀开床罩时[便于就寝]再做打扫吗
when they come to turn down your bed?
为什么我六个月前没遇上你呢
Why didn't I meet you six months ago?
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
您的舒心就是我们的目标
And if there's anything else I can do
如果您有任何需要
to make your stay here more enjoyable,
请致电总台找卡内尔
just ring the concierge and ask for Carnell.
快点吃
Eat fast.
一会儿有服务哦
We're expecting company.
其实
Okay.
这主意也不算太糟
This might not be such a bad idea.
你是怎么理解他说的  "任何需要"
What do you think he meant by "Anything"?
给自己留点时间  放松放松
Take some time for yourself. Relax.
我知道那只是个比喻
I know it's a figure of speech,
但他好像真的有在强调  "任何"
but he really did seem to underline the "Anything."
找人聊聊吗
Maybe talk to someone?
已经安排好了
Already scheduled.
真的吗
Really?
我又不傻
I'm not an idiot.
我知道我需要帮助
I know I need help.
好吧
Okay.
那也  挺好
That's...great.
我指的是心理咨询师什么的
I meant, like, a counselor.
我知道
I know.
但你指的是小姐
But you meant a hooker.
没错
Yeah.
慢慢来嘛
Baby steps.
豪斯抛弃我们了
House screwed us.
医生们花了十年时间
Ten years of doctors
把他重新拼接了一遍
cobbling him back together.
四肢里全是金属棒
Metal rods in every limb.
脊柱靠钢针固定
Pins stabilizing his spine.
颅骨里
Five screws
还有五颗钛钉和一块钛板
and a titanium plate in his skull.
没法做核磁共振
Can't do MRIs.
X光可能也没什么用处
X-rays are probably gonna be useless as well.
每块金属都会阻挡射线显影
Every piece of metal is gonna obscure something.
豪斯根本没病
And House isn't sick.
你为什么这么说
Why would you say that?
卡迪把豪斯甩了
Cuddy dumped House.
他丢下工作躲起来自己舔伤去了
He's out somewhere expecting us to indulge him
就盼着我们会惯着他
while he ignores his job and licks his wounds.
卡迪把他甩了吗
Cuddy dumped him?
别这样  你别搅进来
Don't do that. Don't get sucked in.
他爱她  怎么会
He loves her. What?
你都不会为他难过一小会儿吗
You can't feel bad for him for five minutes?
我为他感到难过  同时我也希望
I can feel bad for him while still expecting him
他能像个成年人  回来工作
to act like an adult, show up for work,
而不是跑去酗酒
and not go on a booze-,
嗑药  寻欢作乐
Vicodin-, and hooker-filled bender.
以致我们现在
Which is why for now
要独立处理这件案子
we're gonna handle the case without him.
原来是这么回事啊
Oh, is that the reason?
我还以为这都源于你不肯错过
I thought it was because you can't pass up
任何能掌控大局的机会呢
any chance to seize control.
我说了"我们"  还想我"拜托了"吗
I said "We". You want "Pretty please" too?
等等  酗酒招妓什么的我都能理解
Wait. I understand the booze
但维科丁怎么回事
and the hookers, but why Vicodin?
你在这里还真是什么朋友都没有啊
Wow, you really don't have any friends in here, do you?
豪斯嗜维科丁成瘾
House is a Vicodin addict.
已经戒了两年了
He's been clean for two years.
他工作的时候也吃吗
He's used here at work?
没错  这事很麻烦
Yes, that is very troubling.
正如我们的病人
Almost as much as the fact
患有隔肌破裂
that our patient has a ruptured diaphragm,
胸骨骨折  鼻骨断裂
cracked sternum, broken nose,
以及部分听力丧失一样麻烦
and partial hearing loss,
这些可能是由公牛在他身上踩踏所致
which can be explained by a bull jumping on him.
但脑神经功能障碍  低烧
And a neurological disorder, low-grade fever,
恶心  外周肌无力这些症状都无法解释
nausea, and peripheral muscle weakness that can't.
如果听力丧失不是公牛导致的呢
What if the hearing loss wasn't caused by the bull?
他只是刚好在那时发现这点
That's just when he noticed it?
内耳病变会影响平衡
Inner-ear pathology can affect the equilibrium
并引起定向障碍
and cause disorientation,
从而表现为脑神经功能障碍
making it appear to be a neurological disorder.
我们怎么确诊呢
So how do we confirm?
CT只会显示出板子和螺钉
CT is just gonna show us the plate and screws
支撑着的颅骨
holding his skull together.
我们可以做前庭眼反射和眼球震颤电流描记测试
We can do calorics and an ENG.
如果有内耳损伤
If he has inner-ear damage,
就会影响他的平衡
it'll affect his balance.
听上去不错  去吧
Sounds good. Go ahead.
去吧  不是吧
Go ahead? Really?
如果我们中有人不同意呢
What if one of us disagrees?
我恰巧同意福曼
I happen to agree with Foreman.
去做吧
Go do it.
在确立关系之前你就知道他是个瘾君子
You knew he was an addict before you got involved.
我们的关系并非因为
Didn't end the relationship...
你也知道他是个混蛋
You knew he was an ass...
我并非
I didn't end it...
你告诉他你不想他有所改变
You told him you did not want him to change.
我错了
And I was wrong.
你怎么能确定
You don't know that.
你以为你要死了
You thought you were gonna die.
你真觉得那种时候
Do you really think that was the right time
适合作出这种决定吗
to make this kind of decision?
不
No.
但我想过了
But I've thought about it.
想了很多
A lot.
我也没要改变主意
And I haven't changed my mind.
他以为你要死了
He thought you were gonna die.
那种情况下是人都会无所适从
Nobody knows the right way to react in that situation.
再给他一次机会吧
Just give him another chance.
他应得的
He deserves it.
我明白
I know.
但这不是他应不应得的问题
But this isn't about what he deserves.
当不好的事情发生时
When things go wrong,
我不想只是希望我不是独自一人
I don't want to hope that I'm not alone.
我需要知道我并不孤单
I want to know it.
和豪斯在一起
With House...
每当我需要他站出来时
Every time I needed him to step up...
他就是做不到
He's just never gonna be that.
这不是他的错  他就是这样的人
It's not his fault. It's who he is.
我早该知道的
I should have known it.
这是我的错
This is my fault.
他又开始吃维科丁了
Well, he's back on Vicodin.
你也许会想要
So you might want to...
注意下他的新病人
keep an eye on his new patient.
眼球震颤电流描记测试正常
ENG was normal.
就是说他的内耳没有...
Means his inner ear isn't...
白痴们
Morons.
-不是...  -等等
- It wasn't... - Whoa. Wait a second.
这里的音效太美妙了
The acoustics in here are beautiful.
白痴们
Morons!
你说一次
You say it.
白痴们
Morons.
那是谁
Who was that?
卡内尔给我找的
Something Carnell got me.
那理论并非无稽之谈
It wasn't that ridiculous of a theory.
理论很棒
Great theory.
但测试方法太荒谬了
It's a ridiculous test.
你怎么能给骑牛冠军
You can't give a standard balance test
进行标准的平衡测试
to a champion bull rider.
如果你想测试超人的力量
If you're gonna test Superman's strength,
你就需要一个更大的杠铃
you need a bigger barbell.
找个方法  给他测下
Find one, make him lift it,
然后打电话告诉我结果如何
then call me and tell me how high it got.
告诉卡迪偷听是懦夫的表现
And tell Cuddy that spying is for cowards.
随时报告我进展
Just keep me posted.
-会的  -会的
- I will. - I will.
你说过我的内耳没问题
You said my inner ear was fine.
先前的测试是为普通人准备的
Previous test was for regular people.
上次意外中你受伤严重
You were banged up pretty bad in the accident.
但考虑到你的运动能力
But given your athletic ability...
不是意外
Wasn't no accident.
那头牛是故意的  有阴谋的
That bull had malice and forethought.
你的意思是有预谋的
Uh, you mean aforethought.
随便吧  他被惹毛了
Whatever. He was pissed.
你怪他吗
Can you blame him?
当然不
Not at all.
如果他吃粮不干活
If he don't do what he gets paid for,
我就没活干拿不了钱
I don't get to do what I get paid for.
你就没想过
You ever think of getting paid
要干点别的吗
for doing something else?
你已经快没骨头可断了
You're running out of bones to break.
你会考虑做你不喜欢的事吗
You ever think of doing something you don't love?
骑牛虽然有不好的一面
It has its downside,
但哪件事不这样啊
but everything does.
没什么能比得上那八秒钟
There ain't nothing like those eight seconds.
旅行啦  和粉丝见面啦
Traveling around, getting to meet the fans,
那也很不错  如果你明白我的意思的话
that ain't so bad either, if you know what I mean.
好了  现在要做什么
All right, now what?
我们会摇晃这个台子
We're gonna start rocking the platform
并且改变你的视野
and changing your visual field
你只能用右脚来保持平衡
while you balance on just your right leg.
给  莱恩
Here you go, Lane.
我会从低速开始的
I'm gonna start slow.
如果你感觉到
If you start to experience
恶心或者定向障碍
any nausea or disorientation,
告诉我们  我们就停止测试
just let us know and we'll stop the test.
明白
You got it.
这太棒了
That is amazing.
我们可以停了
We can stop.
很明显他的内耳
There's obviously nothing wrong
没有任何问题
with his inner ear.
现在呢
Now what?
我并非在问我的老板
And I direct that question not to my boss,
而是在问任何知道答案的人
but to anyone who has an answer.
如果问题不在他耳朵里  那就是他脑子
If it's not in his ear, it's got to be his brain.
但如果我们没办法成像  我们怎么
But if we can't get any images, then how do we...
看来你们这里的水管生锈了
Looks like you guys got some rusty pipes.
这水是棕色的
This water's brown.
不是水管的问题
That's not from the pipes.
是你的嘴
It's from your mouth.
能递给我
Can you pass me the, um...
怎么花了这么久
What took you so long?
他的耳朵没问题
There's nothing wrong with his ears,
但他的痰中带血
but he's got blood in his sputum.
你没回答我的问题
Doesn't answer the question.
我们不是为了避开你
We weren't avoiding you.
我们花了一点时间来想
It took us a little time to think up
一种没人曾考虑过的诊断测试办法
a diagnostic test no one's ever thought up before.
我接受你们的道歉
Apology accepted.
可能是唾液腺里的肿瘤引起的
It could be a tumor in a salivary gland.
我们应该做个腮腺活检
We should get a parotid biopsy.
你好有爱啊
Oh, that's so cute.
你竟然在反抗代班当值的头头
You're fighting over who's in charge.
消化道出血更能解释
GI bleed's more likely
恶心想吐及身体虚弱
to explain the nausea and weakness.
现在谁当家
Who's in charge?
豪斯  只要你不在这里
House, as long as you're not here,
就得有人做最后的
someone has to have the final...
那我换个表达方式吧
Let me rephrase.
现在谁是你们大爷
Who's your daddy?
不如我换个说法吧
Let me rephrase.
你最好下定决心
You have to decide
是要振作起来  浪子回头
if you're gonna buck up, get out of bed,
继续工作
and do your job,
还是要沉湎于顾影自怜
or if you're gonna wallow in self-pity.
我只有这两个选择吗
Those my only two choices?
能容我指出顾影自怜的是你吗
Or can I also point out the self-pity coming from you?
你不就因为
You're just annoyed
自己的婚姻完蛋时无人问津
because when your relationship ended,
连你自己都不在乎而恼火吗
no one gave a crap, including you.
你这话怎么说都不对
That is not true in so many ways.
奇斯  别再跟福曼抬杠了
And, Chase, stop screwing with Foreman.
福曼  你错
And, Foreman, no.
除非等到电话遭逆转发明而消失
Till the telephone gets uninvented,
你们屋里这群人
no one in that room
就只有我赋予的权利
needs more authority than I give them,
而我现在就赐予你为病人
and right now I give you the authority
做消化道内镜检查和腮腺活检的权力
to scope his GI tract and biopsy his parotid.
你可以拿起听筒了
And you can pick up the phone.
等等  豪斯  我们是不是该更担心你一些
Wait, House, should we be more worried about you?
你在服用维科丁吗  如果是这样
Are you on Vicodin? Because if you are,
也许你就不该发号施令了
you probably shouldn't be ordering procedures.
我没吃维科丁
I am not on Vicodin.
做检查去
Do the tests.
我和手摇风琴先生还有个约
I have to see a man about a hurdy-gurdy.
你真的相信豪斯没嗑维科丁吗
You really think House isn't using Vicodin?
这事真的有让你担心吗
Does it actually worry you?
要是他在给自己开药
If he's self-prescribing meds,
可能会影响他的判断力
that could affect his judgment.
所以这让你担心了吗
And does that worry you?
你是在挖苦我吗
Are you being sarcastic?
他这不合规矩的做法影响到他的判断力
If his rule-breaking is affecting his judgment,
那你就可以正当插手  担你的心去
then you can step in and you can worry,
可如果这让他不断迸发出
but if he's just coming up with ideas
该我们想到却没想到的点子
that we haven't thought of but we should have,
那我们就只要闭嘴照做便是
then our job is to shut up and do it.
还有你看上这家伙哪点了
And what do you see in this guy?
什么  你说谁
Hmm? What? Who?
你觉得我对我们的病人有好感
Oh. You think I'm attracted to our patient?
没错
Right.
这不符合规定
It's against the rules,
所以你肯定不会采取行动的
so you wouldn't do it.
他是个有男子气概的傻瓜
He's a macho half-wit.
你没有任何理由喜欢上这样的人
You have every reason to not be attracted to him,
所以我才好奇
which is why I ask the question.
你怎么就看上他了
Why are you attracted to him?
-停  -我只是
- Stop it. - I'm just...
-不不不  拿出视镜  -但我没看到
- No, no, no. Take out the scope. - But I don't see...
不是显示器  看他的眼睛
Not the monitor. Look at his eyes.
巩膜呈黄色  已做X光检查
Sclerae turned yellow. Did X-rays.
看上去他肝脏里有个团块
Looks like there's a mass in his liver,
但被他固定肋骨的金属棒挡住了
but the conductive metal rod in his ribs is blocking it.
努力去实现吧  如他们所言
Making it, as they say,
哪怕这与叫会手摇风琴的妓女一样难
as tough to find as a hooker who can play the hurdy-gurdy.
如果你有什么想法  麻烦你
If you have a point, can you please...
打个比方而已
It's an expression.
意思是说虽然那不容易
Means it's tough,
但明显依旧可行
but apparently it can be done.
如果我们没有任何设备
If we don't have any equipment...
你们有双眼
You have eyes.
可不是透视眼
Not that see through stuff.
显然不是
Obviously.
你想要我们把他切开吗
You want us to cut him open?
只有你们想弄明白
Only if you want to see
他哪里出了问题才需要
what's wrong with him.
听过《自由鸟》吗
Do you know Free Bird?
你看到了吗
Do you see what I see?
没看到
No.
一点没错
Exactly.
再吸一点
More suction.
这怎么可能
That's impossible.
我肯定在X光片上看到团块了
I definitely saw a mass on the X-rays.
现在没了
It's gone now.
这是个团块
It's a mass...
接着就消失了
And then it's not.
你要不要  介绍一下我们
You, uh, gonna introduce us?
小组成员  见过杜可
Team, meet Duke.
是安卡
Anke.
是安卡吗  我怎么会想成杜可的
Anke? How'd I get Duke?
豪斯  你叫了多少鸡
House, how many prostitutes have you had?
是说吃的鸡吗
As in eaten?
这辈子吃的  还是就今年吃的
Ever? This year?
睡过的  从你住进来以后
Slept with. Since you've been here.
就一人幸免
All but one.
她帮我报税来着
She did my taxes.
另一方面
On the other hand,
已经钻出他小肠的绦虫
tapeworm that burrowed outside his intestinal...
我们会在粪便涂片中找到虫卵
We would have seen eggs on a fecal smear
或发现系统性嗜酸性粒细胞增多
or systemic eosinophilia.
脱落的囊肿呢
Detached cyst?
不可能在一小时之内移位那么远
Couldn't migrate that far in one hour.
我们又不是无所事事
We haven't been sitting on our hands
坐等你的灵感迸发
just waiting for your brilliance to kick in.
好吧  那你们是怎么排除
Okay, so how did you shoot down
间歇性肿大的淋巴结的呢
intermittently swollen lymph node?
那就是说这是感染造成的
That would mean it's some kind of an infection,
我们要做腰椎穿刺
which would mean we'd have to do a spinal tap.
可鉴于他目前颅骨骨折
But with his recent skull fractures,
可能会导致颅内压增高
it could be an increased ICP.
他可能会脑疝
His brain could herniate.
那做脑室穿刺呢
What about a ventricular puncture?
听起来不错
Sounds good.
你们认为直接给他大脑刺一针
You think sticking a needle directly into his brain
会比刺他腰椎安全吗
would be less dangerous than sticking it in his spine?
我也就随口一说
It's probably a push.
我只是想让你们出去
I'm just trying to get you out of here,
因为床单以下
because underneath this sheet,
小家伙起床了
stuff is going on.
选个地方来一针就是了
Just pick a spot and stick a needle in it.
你们想钻开我的颅骨
You want to drill through my skull
就因为有个不存在的团块吗
because of a mass that's not there?
原先存在的  意味着有地方出了问题
It was there, which means something is wrong.
我们得把它弄明白
We need to find it.
你想给谁打电话吗
Is there anybody you'd like us to call?
打给你希望陪在你身边的人
Someone that you'd like to be here with you?
妻子  或者是女朋友
Maybe a wife or girlfriend?
没有  我家人都在俄克拉荷马州
No, my family's all back in Oklahoma,
演出团的那些家伙
and the guys on the circuit
正在卡尔加里进行下一轮骑术表演
are in Calgary at the next rodeo.
真是太糟了
Ah, that's too bad.
能有个关心你的人在身边
It's nice to have somebody nearby
和你说说话是件幸福的事
you can talk to who cares.
你还好吧
You okay?
你刚说  "能有个关心你的人在身边
You just sang, "It's good to have somebody near by
和你说说话是件幸福的事"
to talk to who cares."
行了  我喜欢他  又怎样
Okay, fine. I like him. So what?
开玩笑的吧  我真弄不懂为什么
No kidding. I just can't figure out why.
我也弄不懂
Neither can I.
没有异样
Looks clear.
没有发炎的症状
Nothing is suggesting inflammation.
出问题了
Something's wrong.
血氧饱和度急剧下降
O-2 stats are plummeting.
需要插管
We need to intubate.
把手术台放低
Drop the table.
我插不进管去
I can't get it in.
呼吸道梗阻  快去拿气管切开包
The airway's blocked. Get the trach kit.
血氧饱和度回升
O-2 are going back up.
这是什么味道啊
What's that smell?
他刚排便了吗
Did he defecate?
看起来不像
Doesn't look like it.
我觉得是脚的问题
I think it's his feet.
绝对是脚的问题
It's definitely his feet.
求求你别这样
Please don't.
这把弓真不错
That is a nice bow.
这也曾是扇漂亮的门
That was a nice door.
记在我的帐上
Put it on my tab.
我们来点刺激的怎么样
Let's say we take it up a notch.
是啊  你真逗
Yeah, right. Very funny.
你不相信我吗
You don't trust me?
当然不
No.
我来
I'll do it.
我们有一个参与者了
And we have a gamer.
别啊  兄弟
Oh, come on, man.
你不会玩真的吧
You can't be serious.
为什么不啊
Why not?
出了问题
Anything goes wrong,
就带她去见医生
we just take her to the doctor.
而且我离她只有八步远
And I'm only eight paces away.
-豪斯  -我挺喜欢你的  卡内尔
- House... - I like you, Carnell.
别把这感觉毁了
Don't ruin it.
脚臭可能是由糖尿病
Stinky feet can point to diabetes,
脚癣  坏疽引起的  选一个吧
athlete's foot, or gangrene... Pick one.
不要
No!
都不是
Uh, none.
没有一个会导致血痰
None of those cause bloody sputum
或者团块消失的
or disappearing masses.
别别  别  别
No. No. No. No.
你会杀了她的
You're gonna kill her.
别这么做  卡内尔
Don't do that, Carnell.
他们会以为
They might get the idea
我正要射杀一个妓女呢
that I'm shooting at a hooker.
霉菌感染可能会导致
Fungal infection can cause
足趾间溃疡
ulceration between the toes
而出血可能是
and bleeding could be
脓肿复发导致的
from recurring abscesses
看起来像是复发的团块而已
that appear to be recurring masses.
症状出现在头部或者脚部
Symptoms in the head or feet
说明感染来自心脏
mean the infection would have to be
或者脑部
in the heart or the brain.
我建议先检查心脏
I say we start by looking in the heart,
因为检查装着金属板的大脑
because looking at his brain
有点不大好整
with a metal plate is problematic.
那就用核磁共振检查他的心脏吧
So's MRI'ing his heart.
他靠着一根七厘米长的金属棒
He's got a seven-centimeter conductive metal rod
将肋骨固定在一起
holding his rib together.
那样会将他撕成两半的
It'll rip him in two.
不  只是感觉像是撕成两半了
No, it'll just feel like it's ripping him in two,
实际上可没那么糟
which is much better.
我们可以通过向腹腔
We could minimize the damage
注射冰水来尽量减少伤害
by injecting ice water into his abdominal cavity.
不  求求你  别
No. Please, no.
天啊
Oh, God!
先挂了
Got to go.
快叫救护车
Call an ambulance!
为什么啊
Why?
这还用问为什么吗
What do you mean why?
她受伤了
She's hurt!
她看着可不像受伤哟
She doesn't look hurt.
不是真的吧
No, you didn't.
是真的
Yes, we did.
你真是个混蛋
You're an ass.
帮我去拿巴顿将军四十五号雄驹枪
Okay. Go get me, uh, General Patton's colt 45.
有两道刻痕的那支
The one with the two notches.
他不会给你拿枪来的
He's not getting you a gun.
你朋友知道怎么寻开心
Your friend knows how to have a good time.
核磁共振中的磁铁会加热你体内的金属
The MRI magnets are gonna heat the metal.
会在十五秒中内
Could get to over 300 degrees
超过149度
in 15 seconds.
这就是为什么我们要向你的腹腔内
Which is why we're injecting ice water
注射冰水
into your abdominal cavity.
你会感到前所未有的寒冷
You'll feel colder than you've ever felt,
然后你会变得热辣
and then you'll be hotter...
你会感到前所未有的燥热
Um, you'll feel hotter than you've ever felt.
我们会尽快做完的
We'll try to be as quick as possible.
闭嘴
Shut up.
这真有意思
It's interesting.
不  没什么意思
No, it's not.
这很通俗易懂
It's mundane and simple.
他明显是个优良品种
He's obviously a very blessed specimen,
所以从进化论的角度来看
so from an evolutionary point of view,
他能繁衍健康的后代
he'd produce healthy offspring,
所以我的额前皮质告诉我
so my prefrontal cortex is telling me
我应该和他上床
I should have sex with him.
-就这样吗  -没错
- Oh. Is that all? - Yes.
我大脑的理性部分告诉我他粗俗而且愚蠢
My rational brain knows he's a hillbilly and an idiot.
但不知怎么你大脑理性的部分
And yet somehow your rational brain
没能说服你啊  这很有趣
is losing the argument, which is interesting.
你无聊了
You were bored.
你肯定花了差不多两天时间
You must have spent about two days
策划这次假谋杀  你真是太无聊了
setting up a fake murder, and you were bored.
我好着呢
I'm fine.
你不好
You're not.
而且我担心你会做出更愚蠢的事情
And I'm worried you might do something even stupider.
要不你搬回来和我一起住吧
Why don't you move back in with me?
至少在你重回正轨之前
At least until you get back on track.
太自恋了吧
What an ego.
你以为你是什么知心大哥哥
You think you're some sort of emotional paragon?
我的坚强后盾吗
You're my rock?
我只是想当一个朋友
I'm trying to be a friend.
至少我不会傻到
At least I have the good sense
去娶每个上过床的女人
not to marry every woman I fall into bed with.
或许你该搬过来和我住
Maybe you should move in with me.
都行  如果你希望这样
Either way. If you prefer...
我希望你别再说这事了
I prefer you to stop talking about this.
豪斯  我们还没开始谈呢
House, we haven't even started talking about this
除了你一直在强调说你好着呢
except to establish the fact that you are fine,
但你现在明显不好
which clearly you aren't.
别烦我
Leave me alone!
不行
No.
我们要讨论这个问题
We are gonna talk about this,
并且解决这个问题
and we're gonna deal with this.
就是说我没选择了
So I have no choice?
行吧
Fine.
除非
Unless...
除非  我有选择
Unless...Yes, I do.
我有腿啊
I do have legs.
看来你那高明的计划里没考虑这个因素啊
I see you didn't factor those into your brilliant plan.
莱恩  你能尽量保持不动吗
Lane, can you try to hold still?
我在尽力
I'm trying.
非常努力
Real hard.
我必须得说  这哥们真顽强
Guy is tough. I'll give him that.
我的额前皮质也有点兴奋了
My prefrontal cortex is a little aroused.
快点成像
Just get the damn picture.
肋温达到七十度了
Rib temp is at 158.
我还没拍到主动脉足够清晰的图像
I don't have a clear view of his aorta yet.
这样不行  我们得停下
This isn't gonna work. We have to stop.
不  你这是在保护他
No. You're trying to protect him
而不是救他
instead of trying to save him.
他冒烟了
He's smoking.
真的  你个混蛋
Literally, you ass.
再五秒钟
Five more seconds.
不  如果他胸腔没了
No, getting a good image
拍到张好图像
isn't gonna mean anything
还有什么意义
if he doesn't have a rib cage.
有了
Got it.
图像都  都没问题
The images, they're normal.
你最终还是要跟他谈这件事的
You're gonna have to talk to him eventually.
他需要你
He needs you.
我爱他
I love him.
我知道他也爱我
And I know he loves me.
但是我不能
But I just can't...
他的生命中需要你
He needs you in his life.
即使你不和他上床  他依然需要你
Even if you're not sleeping with him, he needs you.
没有你
Without you...
时光不能倒流
You can't go backwards.
我无法解决他的问题
I can't fix his problem.
我就是他的问题所在
I am his problem.
如果感染不是来自心脏
If the infection's not in his heart,
那就是来自大脑了
then it's in his brain.
你们挡住我的阳光了
You're in my sun.
-做个CT  -不行
- Do a CT. - We can't.
他体内有钛板
He has a titanium plate
还有一堆金属钉
and a bunch of metal screws.
那就拿出来呗
So get rid of them.
他的颅骨存在多发线性骨折
His skull has multiple hairline fractures.
拿掉金属板就像是
Removing the metal plate will be like
要拿掉一半蛋壳
removing half an eggshell without
而不弄碎剩下的一半蛋壳一样
cracking the rest of the shell.
不拿出金属片
And not removing the plate
就像是放任鸡蛋去腐烂一样
will be like leaving the egg out to rot.
我们总不能因为每每给他做检查
We can't cut off the top of his head
都无故消失无从确诊的症状
based on a few symptoms that disappear
而掀起他的头盖骨吧
whenever we try to test for them.
如果那个从未消失的症状
What if the one symptom that hasn't disappeared
其实从不存在呢
was never actually there?
他回答问题的时候是不是有停顿
Any delays when he answers questions?
他没有部分听觉丧失
He doesn't have partial hearing loss.
他是在遗失片段
He's missing moments.
据他说在骑牛期间
He reported having something
有过类似复杂性局部癫痫的症状
like a complex partial seizure during a bull ride.
说从那以后就没出现过了
Said it hasn't happened since,
但是如果是他错了呢
but what if he's wrong?
如果从始至终一直是
What if the infection in the brain
大脑中的感染导致的呢
is causing it to happen all the time?
脑电图没有显示任何癫痫的迹象
His E.E.G. didn't show any sign of seizure activity.
我没说是癫痫
I didn't say it was a seizure.
我说的是类似癫痫
I said it was something like a seizure.
那我猜你是准备告诉我们
And I'm guessing you're about to tell us
我们得找个类似脑电图的东西来证明
we need to find something like an E.E.G. to prove...
不是  因为我已经想到用啥了
Nope, 'cause I already got one.
你们想让我唱歌
You want me to sing?
唱《我的邦妮》怎么能
How's singing My Bonnie gonna
帮你们弄清我大脑的情况
help you see inside my brain?
不能
It won't.
它只能证明我们需要
It's just gonna prove that we need
撬开你的脑壳
to cut into your skull,
可是会有点危险的哦
which is gonna be kind of dangerous.
所以你最好能像天使般的唱歌
So you've got a real incentive to sing like an angel.
我们认为你存在短暂昏厥
We think you're having mini blackouts,
但是你的大脑对此无意识
but your brain compensates.
如果有个预设的节奏就不会没意识了
But it can't compensate if there's a preset rhythm.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
看  跟你们说过了
See? Told ya.
莱恩  你唱的完全不着调
Lane, that wasn't even close.
你真牛
That was brilliant.
是啊
Yeah.
我能理解
It's understandable.
我讨厌死你这样了
I hate when you do that.
你对你脑海中我的想法作出反应
You respond to what you think I'm thinking,
因为你觉得我和你以为的一样
because you think that I think like you do.
真是又烦又侮辱人
It's insulting and annoying.
你害怕是因为没有事情能让你兴奋了
You're scared because nothing excites you.
寻欢作乐不能再让你兴奋
Fun doesn't excite you.
医学谜题无法再让你兴奋
Puzzles don't excite you.
还剩下什么呢
What's left?
我想说的是  你没错
And I was saying you're right.
你伤感你郁闷
You're upset. You're depressed.
连五彩的世界都蒙上了一层灰色
Everything's gonna taste a little worse right now,
但这都会过去的
but it'll pass.
我能理解
It's understandable.
你害怕是因为你觉得我就快要崩塌了
You're scared because you think I'm falling apart,
所以你试着说服自己
and you're trying to convince yourself
你不过是想多了而已
that you're overreacting.
一直在响
Keeps ringing.
喂
Yeah.
豪斯  病人大脑里没有感染
House, there's no infection in this guy's brain.
CT没有问题
CT's clean.
那太糟了
Well, that sucks.
现在我们不得不引爆他的心脏了
Now we have to blow up his heart.
我们才不会弄爆他的心脏
We're not blowing up his heart,
因为已经排除心脏的问题了
because we've ruled out his heart.
核磁共振和食道心脏超声均没有显示
MRI and transesophageal echo reveal
任何肿大迹象  团块或者赘生物
no swelling, no masses, no vegetation,
没有任何异常
no sign of anything.
因为我们用错方法了
'Cause we're looking the wrong way.
这管上有一处裂口
There's an imperfection.
怎么找出它的位置
How do you find where?
我不知道  找个放大镜来
I don't know. Get a magnifying glass and...
一吸便知[又意你真差劲]
You suck.
两种理解都没错
Feel free to interpret that both ways.
用吸管吸水
Suck on the straw,
看看哪里漏了
see where the drink leaks.
你是说我们给他的主动脉加压
You're saying we put pressure on his aorta
直到它裂开吗
until it rips open?
你确实了解这么做的后果吧
You do realize the downside of that?
如果我们不弄破它
If we don't rip it,
感染伤害也会
the damage from the infection will,
不过估计就不是在手术台上开腔躺着了
probably not when he's got his chest open in an O.R.
那时就不能在六十秒内缝合裂口
where it can be repaired inside the 60 seconds
他就会因失血过多而死
it'll take him to bleed to death.
这也太扯了
It's a ridiculous idea.
不会有用的
It won't work.
现在如果你不介意的话
Now if you don't mind...
我就去要他关于引爆他心脏手术的许可了
Get this guy's approval to rip his heart open.
我们认为你患有巴尔通体菌感染
We think you have a Bartonella infection,
导致你动脉壁上长了一个霉菌性动脉瘤
which caused a mycotic aneurysm in your aortic wall.
我们得找到它
We need to find it,
也就是说我们得诱发你的主动脉破裂
which means we need to blow up your heart.
而且  是的  这千真万确
And, yes, I'm as serious as a heart attack.
我们准备提升你的血压
We're going to increase your blood pressure
直到动脉壁的薄弱点爆开
until the weak spot in your aortic wall explodes.
但愿我们能在你失血过多
Hopefully we'll be able to fix it
致死前及时缝好
before you bleed to death.
还有疑问吗
Any questions?
没有
Nope.
真的吗
Really?
你都不想知道
You don't even want to know
是否还能做职业骑手吗
if you'll be able to go back to bull riding?
我猜不能了吧
I assume no?
我是说  你都给我开颅了
I mean, you've already cracked open my skull,
现在又打算诱发我主动脉破裂
and now you're gonna blow up my heart.
还以为你热爱制服斗牛呢
Thought you loved those eight seconds.
我是爱
I do.
而你现在告诉我  我得放弃它
And now you're telling me that I got to give them up.
我总能找到其它有爱的事情
I can always find something else to love.
豪斯
House.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
你没指望我同意
You didn't expect me to say yes
你弄爆他的主动脉吧
to rupturing his aorta, did you?
我都没问
Since I didn't ask,
自然指望你一言不发了
I wasn't expecting you to say anything at all.
你没理由相信这能救他的命
You have no reason to believe this will save his life.
是吗
Really?
没理由么  一点也没有
No reason? None at all?
我就是胡乱给他开个胸
I'm just planning on cracking open his chest,
诱发他主动脉破裂  为加收医疗费么
blowing up his heart, what, to pad his bill?
还是你觉得  因为你伤了我的心
Or you think that since you broke my heart
所以我就想折腾他的心
I want to break his.
我不知道
I don't know.
我想也许你在找
I think maybe you're looking for something
让你兴奋的东西
that can excite you.
填补空虚
Fill a void.
这影响了你的判断
And it's affecting your judgment.
你说的对  是
You're right. I am.
我受伤  抑郁  嗨糊涂了的判断
My damaged, depressed, drug-addled judgment
也比你
is still better than yours
抑或这医院任何医生的好
or any other doctor in this hospital,
我的小队会如常手术  救他的命
and my team is gonna do this procedure and save his life.
所以你要么找保安把我们抓走
So you can either have security arrest me and my team,
要么闪开  别挡我的路
or you can get the hell out of my way.
这女人屈服了
And she caves.
开胸器已固定
Rib spreader in place.
心脏看起来没问题
Heart looks good.
主动脉可视
The aorta's exposed.
是你给卡迪打的小报告吧
I take it you ratted me out to Cuddy.
我觉得你不在状态
I think your judgment is compromised.
好吧  不是你
No, you don't.
快点  我两点还要看壁球比赛呢
Come on. I got a squash game at 2:00.
让牛仔小子一步到位吧
Let's give this cowboy a ride.
如果我再注射
If I inject more,
身体其它部分
there won't be any room for the blood
将会供血不足
to go through the rest of his body.
你说的对
You're right.
诱发他主动脉破裂时
Let's make damn sure we don't damage his toes
还他妈要确保他脚趾不受损
while we blow up his heart.
没有气泡  裂伤或缺口出现
No bubbles, no bruising, no gaps.
不管用
It's not working.
管用
Yes, it is.
我错了
I was wrong.
还没
Not yet.
进行搭桥清创
Let's switch him over to bypass for the debridement.
快点  没多少时间了
Come on. We don't have much time.
降低心率  不然
Slow the heart down so it doesn't...
该死
Damn.
血压太高  不能夹住主动脉
We can't clamp the aorta at this pressure.
就算没这些血液阻碍视线也不行
Even if you can see through all the blood.
快夹住
Do it anyway.
快速抽吸  更多纱布
We need suction and more sponges.
流血太快
Leak is too fast.
不  还行  可以修复好
No, it's not. We can fix this.
成功了
It worked.
豪斯  成功了
House, it worked.
听到了
I heard you.
我既然能醒  那八成是手术成功了吧
I'm awake, so I guess it worked.
只要你别让自己的心率过高
As long as you don't get your heart rate too high.
你  最好近期别有性行为
You, uh, probably shouldn't have sex for a while.
我会记住的
I'll keep that in mind.
想找个时间一起逛逛你农场吗
Want to hang out, see your ranch sometime?
可能有点不合适哈
That would probably be inappropriate,
毕竟我是你医生什么的
'cause I'm your doctor and everything.
祝一切顺利
Good luck with everything.
双人份苏格兰威士忌  双人份
Double scotch. Doubled.
兑和  单一纯麦  有个人偏好吗
Uh, blended? Single malt? Any preference?
没
No.
有点吵  不好意思
Yeah, sorry about the noise.
我猜是他们的队赢了
I guess, uh, their team won.
不过还是得和你说
Although I got to tell you,
有时  我也希望自己能那样
sometimes I wish I could still act like that, you know?
纵情愉悦
Just let loose.
那样生活会轻松一点吧
Ah, I guess it's a little easier, though,
无忧无虑的
when you got no troubles.
爸妈买单
Parents still paying your bills.
还有大好人生在前头
Got your whole life ahead of you.
不
No!
青龙入海[抱膝跳水]
Cannonball!
你他妈的在搞什么
What the hell are you doing?
你们赢了之后怎么办
What do you do when you win?
派对
Party!
你们输了之后怎么办
What do you do when you lose?
狂欢
Party harder!